

ROBERT SMITH

Android Application Developer

- info@qwikresume.com
- (123) 456 78 99
- Alabama
- www.qwikresume.com

Professional Summary

Over Seven (7+) years of software development experience with 3+ years of exclusive experience in Android Application development with Android SDK, Android NDK, Eclipse IDE, along with Android ADT plug in developing Native WEB and Hybrid applications.

Work Experience

Android Application Developer

Sears Jan / 2019 - Ongoing Chicago, IL

- Participated in mobile development phases like Designing, Enhancements, Bugfixing and maintenance of the Application.
- Android application development using Java, XML, JSON, GSON, SQLite, Fragments, RetroFit & Picasso.
- Focused on implementing rich user interface per UI/UX and Google's Material Design specifications.
- Maintain the Session Management for the app and Supporting screen orientations (landscape and portrait).
- Extensively utilized Retrofit library with OkHttp for API calls; Used the Picasso library for image caching.
- Designed efficient UI using SearchView, TabLayout, VideoView and ReceylerView.
- Worked on Push Notifications using FCM and integrated it in to the application to send notifications to the users.

Android Developer

Dada Entertainment, NY Jan / 2019 - Ongoing Austin, TX

- Involved in design, development, testing, deployment and maintenance of mobile application.
- Implemented notifications to display the status of the download process and used pending notifications to invoke the media selected by the user.
- Used android content providers for adding wallpapers and ringtones to media gallery after download was completed, then user will be able to view in media.
- Implemented the search functionality allows the users to search ringtones by artist, album or ringtone.
- Used shared preferences for local credit management for displaying available credits in different activities of application.
- Created worker threads for handling long term operations to ensure best ui performance.
- Published the application to android market and updated with new releases.

Education

Bachelors in Computers Science

JN Technological University Jan / 2019 - Ongoing

Skills

Android Application Development with Android SDK

Android NDK

Eclipse IDE

Along with Android ADT PlugIn

Native WEB and Hybrid Applications. Expertise In Developing Native And Hybrid Applications using HTML5

XML

CSS